# Jacob Beeson

Software Developer

## Contact

**Address** 

Austin, TX, 78745

**Phone** 

(336) 486-3317

E-mail

boxnbeeson@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://tinyurl.com/JPBLIn

**Portfolio** 

https://tinyurl.com/JPBPort

#### **Skills**

React.js

Node.is

**Express** 

**JQuery** 

Inquirer

Handlebar.js

MySQL

MongoDB

Bootstrap

HTML

CSS

**JavaScript** 

Software developer utilizing a bachelor's degree in psychology to analyze client demographics for producing effective web design and user experience. Obtained a MERN Full-Stack Certificate through the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. Known for leadership qualities and taking initiative. Successfully led a large organization while in university, restructuring its design based off of attracted demographics while also increasing its membership and community outreach. Proven teamwork capabilities, adaptive nature, and strong interpersonal communication skills through multiple projects.

#### **Education**

2020-05 - 2020-12	Certificate in Full Stack Web Development University Of North Carolina At Chapel Hill
2013-08 - 2019-08	Bachelor of Arts: Psychology University Of North Carolina At Chapel Hill

# **Projects**

#### **PROJECTS**

<u>CoffeeHut</u> | https://tinyurl.com/CoffeeHutGH **Livelink:** https://tinyurl.com/CoffeeHutApp

- Summary: Web-based application where users may customize and order drinks from a local coffee shop
- Role: Front-end development
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, MySQL, Handlebars, Fontawesome

<u>React.js Portfolio</u> | https://tinyurl.com/RPortGH <u>Livelink:</u> https://tinyurl.com/ReactPGH

- Summary: Portfolio designed using React.js
- Role: Sole Developer
- Tools: React.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

**README Generator** | https://tinyurl.com/rmgGH

Tutorial: https://tinyurl.com/rmgtutorial

- Summary: CLI application that a client may use to easily create pre-formatted README.md files
- Role: Sole Developer
- Tools: JavaScript, inquirer, cli

<u>Dinner Dice</u> | https://tinyurl.com/DinDiceGH <u>Livelink:</u> https://tinyurl.com/DinDiceApp

- Summary: Entertainment application allowing users to try new dinner and drink recipes for date night
- Role: Back-end development
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, thecocktaildb/themealdb APIs

<u>Weather Dashboard</u> | https://tinyurl.com/WDashGH **Livelink:** https://tinyurl.com/WDashApp

- Summary: Weather application allowing users to search cities current broadcast and 5-day forecast
- Role: Sole Developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, API integration

# **Professional Experience & Community Involvement**

2014-01 -2019-05

## President, Assistant Coach, Vice-President, Head Trainer, Team Captain, Secretary

Carolina Boxing Club

- 2000+ hours of hands-on training with individuals and groups, ranging from 14 to 55 years of age
- Instructed and supervised team of 10-15 trainers to teach boxing o a club of over 150 members
- Provided daily updates and instructions to a club of 50-150 people
- Implemented a large focus on improving self-esteem, self-efficacy, and community involvement
- Constructed daily boxing technique, conditioning, and training plans
- Provided guidance and emotional support for the club and team

2016-06 -2019-05

### Security / Bartender

Pantana Bob's

- Fostered teamwork and leadership skills for a high-stress environment
- Developed the ability to defuse violent situations and resolve issues among patrons

<sup>\*</sup>All professional experience may be found under "CV" on my portfolio\*